Nandini Morla

Full-stack Web Developer/Software Developer

+1(385) 464-9601, nandinimorla2520@gmail.com, linkedin.com/nandinimorla/, bit.ly/nandinimorla

Experienced Software Developer specializing in web applications(front-end & back-end). Excellent problem-solving and analytical skills, with the ability to quickly grasp complex technical concepts and provide innovative solutions. Strong communication and interpersonal skills, with the ability to effectively collaborate with team members.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Programming Languages: HTML5, CSS, JavaScript, JQuery, TypeScript, Ajax, XML, Java, C/C++, Python, SQL.

Libraries & Frameworks: Node.js, Jquery, Ajax, Django, Express.js, Spring Boot, React.js, Vue.js, Angular, numpy, matplotlib, pandas.

Core Competencies: Data Structures & Algorithms, Git, Linux, Object Oriented Programming, ML, Deep Learning, Gen AI. **Database, Version Control & Tools**: Github, Babel, MySQL, PostgreSQL, Oracle, Wordpress.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Tiny Archives Remote, USA

Computer Science Intern

June 2024 – Present

- I Craft web applications for Tiny Archives FACTool using Reactjs, jsx, and Django frameworks.
- Provide database support, backend development, and global search functionality.
- Developing a chatbot called rosie for our FACTool using NLP and Langchain.

Power Changes Lives

Remote, USA

Web Developer and Designer Intern

April 2024– Present

- Pioneered the design of a cutting-edge front-end interface for a 360-degree photobooth project and redesigned the Power Changes Lives website.
- Implement captivating home pages, dynamic headers, and hamburger menus to enhance user engagement and navigation efficiency.

SUNY New Paltz, Department of Science & Engineering

New Paltz, USA

Teaching Assistant, Operating Systems

January 2023-May 2024

- I assisted in teaching Unix commands, Linux and operating systems concepts to undergraduate students.
- Conducted weekly tutorials, and lab sessions to practically show the real-time working of paging, segmentation, deadlocks, memory allocations etc.
- Evaluated the lab reports and assigned the grades based on students' lab sessions.

Virtusa Remote, India

Intern

October 2020-April 2021

• Developed Consolidated dashboard to fetch overall data analysis from AWS, GCP and Azure using PowerBi.

EDUCATION

State University of New York at New Paltz

August 2022 - May 2024

Master of Science in Computer Science

PUBLICATIONS

Face Mask Detection using Machine Learning Techniques - IEEE Paper Publication.

ACHIEVEMENTS

- Teaching assistant for all four semesters of the Master's Degree Program.
- Awarded the Merit Outstanding Student award in the Master's Program.